jbc.org 2018-12-29

# ASBMB Privacy Policy

This privacy policy establishes how the American Society for Biochemistry and Molecular Biology (ASBMB) uses and protects information you give ASBMB when you use this website.

ASBMB is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. If we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

ASBMB may change this policy periodically by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you agree with any of the changes. This policy is effective from May 15, 2018.

### What we collect

Information submitted on the ASBMB’s websites is collected, stored and processed in the United States. If you are outside the United States, your personal data and other information will be transferred to the United States. By using our website and services, you agree to the transfer of your personal data as described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to such cross-border transfers of your personal data, please do not submit it through our website.

We may collect the following information: 

  * Name and job title
  * Contact information including email addresses
  * Other information relevant to member and non member surveys and/or offers

### Financial Information

Financial information may be collected online when individuals register for meetings, order publications or make payment for membership. The online forms are secured using SSL protocols. This encrypts the entered information during the transaction to protect the information from unauthorized access. The SSL certs are provided by trusted and established certificate vendors. The ASBMB does not store any financial information collected online.

### What we do with the information collected

We use this information to understand your interests and provide you with excellent service, and for the following specific purposes: 

  * Internal record keeping of your account
  * To improve our services to our members and others
  * We may periodically send promotional emails about new products, services or other information which we think you may find interesting using the contact information you have provided
  * We may contact you for market research purposes or to customize our website.

### Security

We are committed to ensuring your information is secure. To prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, we have physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

### Cookies

A cookie is a file that stores data on a user’s computer or returns it to the web server. The data in the file is information a user has entered using an online form, or generic information about the visiting user, such as an IP address or browser type. A cookie can be either temporary or persistent, but ultimately the user is in control of it and how any cookie is stored through their web browser. The ASBMB requires cookies to provide functionality on certain areas of the website. If cookies are not enabled, those areas will not function as intended and the ASBMB will be unable to provide the full range of services to the user. ASBMB does not store any financial information in cookies.

### Links to other websites

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, if you use these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we are not responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you may provide while visiting such sites, and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement.

We will not sell or distribute your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so. We may use your personal information to send you promotional information which we think you may find of interest.
